Miller, J. Gormly Additional Files /4228
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
J. Gormly Miller Additional Files
1962-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, J. Gormly
/4228
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8055531
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Nicole Dardia/Casey Westerman, May 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 04, 2016
Biographical / Historical
J. Gormly Miller (1975-1979) - J. Gormly Miller received a Bachelor of Arts degree from University of Rochester in 1936 and a bachelor's degree in Library Service from Columbia University in 1938. He worked at the Rochester Public Library from 1938 to 1942, and served in the United States Army during World War II. In 1946, Miller came to Cornell University as a librarian in the newly established School of Industrial and Labor Relations. From 1949 until his retirement in 1977, he served on the faculty of the ILR School as an associate professor and then a full professor, teaching courses in research methods. He held numerous consulting and special assignments, including advising the Department of Labor Relations at the University of Chile in Santiago on library development plans in 1961, and advising the U.S. Department of Labor on expanding library resources. From 1962 to 1970, he served as Assistant Director of personnel and budget for libraries. In 1970, he left for Geneva, Switzerland to become deputy chief of the Central Library and Documentation Branch of the United Nations' International Labor Agency. Miller returned to Cornell in 1975 to assume the position of Director of the Cornell University Libraries. Under his administration, the library's total collection grew to more than four million volumes. Miller strengthened library rules and regulations to fight theft and vandalism. Space continued to be a problem, and the first off-site storage facility was built in 1979. During Miller's stay at Cornell University, he actively participated in local government. He was an Ithaca alderman from 1959 to 1963 and again in 1968, when he was chairman of the Ithaca City Charter Revision Commission and co-chairman of the Common Council's Finance Committee. He retired from his post as University Librarian in 1979, but returned to serve as Acting Librarian in 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4139: Martin P. Catherwood Library Librarian's Office Additional Files /4170: J. Gormly Miller Additional Papers /4177: J. Gormly Miller Additional Papers /4192: Martin P. Catherwood Library Librarian's Office Additional Files /4201: Martin P. Catherwood Library Librarian's Office Additional Files
Miller, J. Gormly; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8055531
- Personal (correspondence, resume), 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ILR Library, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cornell University Library, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ILR Library, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cornell University Library-General, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Blue Cross, Blue Shield, Empire Medical (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cornell University Library Organization and Structure, Issues and Problems (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell University Library - General, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Scope and Contents
  May-June 1987
- Cornell University Libraries-General, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cornell University Libraries-Banquets, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Reunion '87
- Personal, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  July 1986.
- Cornell Faculty Memorial Statements, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  G.F. Shepherd(1978-79), Felix Reichman (1988- 89)
- Letters of Reference, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Ingeborg Wald
- Personal Messages, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Personal Files, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  January 1986-June 1986
- Letters of Reference, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Personal/Official Cornell University Library, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Personal Curriculum Vita, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- University Librarian Searches, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Syracuse University, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Tompkins County Economic Opportunity Corporation, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Library Staff and Personnel, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cornell Libraries-General - Memorial Statements-Staff Notes, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- International Labor Organization (ILO), Geneva, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  AIL Newsletters, Correspondence
- Retirement Documents, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Report of a Review of Staffing Levels Within CU Library System by JGM, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Consulting Projects-University of Massachusetts, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Personal-ILO Geneva, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wagner College Case, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Schickel Design and Development Company, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ILR School Official Correspondence, Forms, etc, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Quasi Official Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Fondazione Luigi Einaudi (Professor Mario Einaudi), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Microcomputers in Library Automation, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CU Library Staff Directory, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Eastwood Commons Directory 1987, Phone Numbers PBM List 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- ILR Directory, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Personal Correspondence, 1974-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  1974, 1980, 1984, 1995
- Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians (PFH Retirement), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  April 1993.
- International Labor Office-Official Appointment Documents, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ILO Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Preliminary Review of Potential Microcomputer Use in Libraries, JGM, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Cornell University Libraries General, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Syracuse University School of Information Studies, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Summer Session 1981 Lecture Notes
- Olin Library, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- CU Central Library Study, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Republican Senatorial Inner Circle, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence-William B. Groat Award, John Schappi Nomination, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Library Management Services -Correspondence, 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Christmas Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Personal, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Memorial Speech Kathryn Bischoff (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Saul Warren Fund for Minority Studies, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)